Welcome into a very special version of
Next Man Up. We are here for free agent
Fridays in the Big Bear AI Command
Center studio and I'm here with a
familiar face. Was our QB1 for a little
while last year. Welcoming in Marcus
Mariota who decided to come back on a
one-year deal. Congrats, brother.
>> Thank you very much. Excited to be here,
man. Appreciate it.
>> I mean, there was a market for you.
Everybody's looking at Marcus Mariota
and saying, "Wow, what he did last year,
almost 1,700 yards, 10 touchdowns. We
want a piece of that." But you said,
"You know what? I want to stay here and
continue to build with the Commanders."
Why was that?
>> It starts with the coaching staff. Uh, I
love Q. I think he's built an
unbelievable atmosphere to come play
football. Um, and I've seen other parts
of it, right? I've been on five other
teams and like the opportunity to be in
this setting, um, was one that I just
didn't want to pass up.
>> What was last year like for you, man?
You've had such an interesting career
since being in the NFL, even back in
college. Last year seemed like it was
one of one for you though, being able to
step up as that starting quarterback and
play a lot of games. What was it like
for you, man?
>> Yeah, it was unique. Very, very unique.
And football kind of does that, right?
It it puts you in different situations
and different scenarios. But, um, I
loved just being in the arena. I loved
playing. Um, the circumstances weren't
great. You never want to see Jay go
down. you never want to see a one of
your guys go down, but to play it just
kind of reminded me of why I do it. Um,
you know, you go through segments in
your career where I didn't get to play a
whole lot. I was kind of coming in
sparingly, and to come back and to to
really play a lot, um, just solidified
how much I love playing and love the
game.
>> What did you learn about yourself last
season during that time?
>> Yeah, I just I learned a lot about just
how to really be a leader, how to uh
bring people together. Um, you know, the
season didn't go the way that we wanted
to, but I thought the effort, um, the
drive, the motivation was there
throughout the entire year, and a lot of
that had to stem from really the
coaching staff and Q bringing the
positive energy day in and day out. Um,
but I think a season like that sets a
solid foundation for what's to come. And
I think our guys are excited to get back
out there and get going. And you've
mentioned Coach Quinn a couple of times
now and it seems like everybody that
sits in this chair has nothing but high
praise, not only for him as a coach, but
him as a man and the way he treats y'all
as players and as men. What was that
conversation like with Dan Quinn when
you let him know, "Hey, bro, we running
it back one more year."
>> It was special, man. You know, uh we
have a connection going to Hawaii. Um he
spends a lot of time there and he lives
like less than 10 minutes from where my
parents live right now and um just to
call him the excitement like it feels
good and it feels good to be wanted. It
feels good to be a part of something
like this and I'm just excited to play
for him.
>> And then you hear the news that David
Blau is going to be our offensive
coordinator. Somebody you're very
familiar with as well. Somebody that's
worked hand in hand with you and Jaden.
How excited are you about that news,
man?
>> Oh, fired up. Uh Blau's going to be
awesome. I really believe that he for a
young cat has been through a lot. He's
gone to a lot of different systems, has
played a little bit of football, and he
understands what that mentality, what
that mindset is of the quarterback. And
for us in our room, like to have that
type of friendly understanding and and
know that he's going to do everything in
his power to put forth the best for us
um gives us confidence and we're excited
to play for him as What have you seen in
those rooms, in those meetings that does
make you have that confidence in him and
that does make you say this is the
perfect guy to lead this offense?
>> Yeah. Well, first and foremost, just his
understanding of football. Um, you know,
he's younger than me and I feel like he
has an even better understanding of what
um an offense should look like, how the
system should be, and he's really
solidified in a lot of convictions. And
I think that's pretty cool. Like um a
young cat might come in and be like,
"I'll try to do this. So, I'll try to do
that. But he has a very pinpoint thought
of what he wants the offense to look
like. And I think that's going to
breathe confidence into everybody. And
from from the moment that I met him, I
could see just like how smart and how
creative he is. And I'm excited to get
to work with him and and see what it all
looks like.
>> And it seems as if he really promotes
competition. Like he's even competing
with you guys, playing throwing drills
and stuff like that. When you are a
competitor, like man, you're a Heisman
winner, man. You're a top pick. when you
are a competitor but also being asked to
be a leader and a mentor but also keep
your mind and body ready to play at any
time man what is that balance like
>> it's a beautiful balance and I think
that's what continues to draw me back um
it asked a lot of me as a person but
also it's
>> helping me become the best version of
myself um
>> I really believe com competitiveness
um motivation determination comes from
just trying to be the best version of
yourself And every single day, Blau's
going to demand that from us. And when
that room is set to that standard, I
think really all of us can't help but
get better. And that's really what it
comes down to. I just I'm just kind of
chasing the best version of myself and
whatever that looks like.
>> Um, and I feel like this type of culture
and atmosphere allows that for me.
>> It's dope to hear you talk about
yourself building and you helping
yourself because we know that you're a
big mentor here. We know that you're a
big leader in that locker room. We know
that you were brought in to help teach
Jaden Daniels the way, right? Two
Heisman guys, two very similar style of
quarterbacks. What has it been like
mentoring the young Jaden Daniels? We
hear so much about him, but I feel like
your vantage point of Jaden is probably
different than anybody else's.
>> It's It's been a blessing.
>> He is uh he's a breath of fresh air,
especially I think in just today's world
of like
he's so humble, but also he's so
confident at the same time. and I just
learned a lot from him. So, the more
that we continue to to grow together, I
think the more that we'll we'll make
each other better. Um, but he's a
special talent, man. And the more that
we can continue to uplift him. Um,
I' I've said it a number of times, but
the sky's is the limit for him. And
we're all here just trying to help him
find that. And, um, it's cool because
he's very appreciative. I think there's
times where you can see guys, maybe
younger guys, they think they kind of
figure it out. And he's never been that
way. He's always asking questions. He's
always trying to observe. And the more
that we can continue to breathe life
into that, um, we'll we'll find he's
going to be one of the better players in
this league.
>> What are some of those questions that he
does hit you with?
>> It's easy. It's like just from, hey,
what what' you see here? Or, you know,
in this play, how would you read it? Um,
it could be things like off the field,
um, you know, how to handle certain
things, um, media requirements. Um, and
then sometimes it's just BSing and
sometimes that's the best part of it,
right? Like that position is arguably
the hardest in sports and sometimes you
just need some time to be able just to
talk story and chill out and for us in
the quarterback room like we can kind of
provide that for him. We can be that
sounding board. So, um, he's played a
lot of football now. Um, so the more
that we can kind of get him to feel like
himself and feel normal, um, I think the
the more that he'll play to the best of
his strengths.
>> And I think when talking about a guy
like Jaden Dams, because he's always so
smile and positive, I think people
forget how much he went through last
year. Not just dealing with all the
injuries, not just dealing with the
different contract talks, all that
different stuff. He lost a close loved
one. How have you helped him through
those hard times? Because it's easy to
be smiling. It's easy to be up when
things are going good, but it's really
shows you what kind of man you are when
you're going through those hard times.
You got to see him go through these hard
times. What has that been like?
>> Yeah. He again, he doesn't change his
persona perspective at all. And I got to
give a lot of credit to that. I got a
lot of respect for it because it's easy
to feel down on yourself when you're
injured. It's it's easy to kind of box
yourself in a little bit when things
around you seem to be going a little
astray. So he never was like that. Um
very involved um very happy as usual and
I think that in itself towards the end
of the year especially how everything
kind of fell into place um was good for
the entire team to see and he was
willing to be out there to work um to
get better and I think it's just
creating that solid foundation that we
need moving forward.
>> Man and it's just so great to talk to
you man. I love just hearing about how
you're still working on yourself. How
you're still building, trying to
improve, because you could say, you know
what, I'm done and I've done everything
I've needed to do, but you're still
working at it. Last question for you,
Marcus. What is Marcus Mariota's goals
for himself coming into this season?
>> First and foremost, um be the best
healthwise. Um you know, I got banged up
towards the end of the year, so getting
healthy. And then secondly, just helping
our entire team uh learn the new system,
learn the transition that we're going
through. And um whatever that looks
like, um whatever my role is again, and
uh whether it's to play, whether it's to
mentor, whether it's um to do whatever,
uh I'm willing to do that. And I'm just
thankful to be here in this spot. And I
can continue to try to be the best
version of myself. Um and I'm excited to
see what this all looks like.
>> A great player, an even greater man,
man. Congratulations on all your
success, man. Congratulations on another
contract. Nothing is promised here in
the NFL, man. So, shout out to your boy.
You're looking clean. Got the suit on.
Commandis, family. We are here for our
first episode of this off seasonason of
free agency Friday's next manup version
here with Marcus Mariota. He's going to
go buy me breakfast and my man just got
the bag. Appreciate you, Marcus.
>> Thank you, brother. Appreciate it.